A Guide to the Papers of Thomas Taylor Hammond 1949-1992
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Thomas Taylor Hammond 1949-1992
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
This collection consists of ca.4,000 items,(30 Hollinger boxes, 1 cubic box and 155 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions except for student papers that have been graded. Boxes 28 and 29
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library by Charles T. Evans, Northern Virginia Community College, Loudoun Campus, 100 Harry Flood Byrd Highway, Sterling, VA 20164-8699 on November 7, 2001 and November 11, 2002.
Biographical/Historical Information
Thomas Taylor Hammond, a distinguished professor of history emeritus of the University of Virginia, a specialist in Russian and Slavic studies, an astute observer and researcher of communist revolutions and post World War II Soviet expansion initiatives, a prolific author and lecturer, a skilled photographer and an active civil rights advocate was born on September 15, 1920, in Atlanta, Georgia, the son of Percy Waters (a journalist) and Elizabeth (Denman) Hammond.
Hammond was educated at the University of Mississippi (B.A., 1941) and took graduate studies in economics at the University of North Carolina (M.A., 1943). After serving in the Navy in the Pacific in World War II, he taught history at Emory University in Atlanta, and served as assistant professor of history at Louisiana State University in Baton Rouge. Hammond then continued graduate work in Russian History Studies at Columbia University's Russian Institute (M.A. 1948, Ph.D., 1954).
At the time when Hammond was completing his work at the Russian Institute, Dumas Malone, who was a friend and who was then teaching at Columbia, arranged an interview for him for a position at the University of Virginia in Charlottesville that led to his appointment in 1949 as assistant professor in the department of history.
Over the period of the next 42 years, Hammond taught courses on Soviet history and Soviet foreign policy. He rose to full professor in 1963, and became identified as the University's first Russian specialist. His concerted efforts at expanding research and faculty involvement in his area of study, led to his founding and directing a Center for Russian and Slavic Studies at the University in the mid-1960's. At that time, he also served as president of the Southern Conference of Slavic Studies (1964-1965) and, in later years, president of the Conference on Slavic and East European History (1982-1983).
Hammond was also the holder of many fellowships including the Fulbright, Guggenheim, Carnegie, Ford and Rockefeller Foundations. He was a featured speaker at numerous scholarly conferences and he lectured at the Military Academy at West Point, the Naval War College, the State Department's Foreign Service Institute and at many local and state-wide civic and educational organizations.
Hammond did comprehensive research in his field of study on his many visits outside of the United States. He traveled extensively throughout the USSR and Eastern Europe during the period of the Cold War doing research at the Moscow University and interviewing people in all walks of life. As a skillful photographer, he compiled a massive collection of photo slides, many of which he used to illustrate his lectures and some of which he incorporated in his articles written for the National Geographic Magazine in September, 1959, ("A First Look at the Soviet Union") and in March, 1966, ("An American in Moscow").
The publication of Hammond's writings appeared in journals such as Foreign Affairs, Slavic Review, American History Review, Orbis, and Political Science Quarterly and in numerous other journals in which he published over 100 book reviews. In 1976, Hammond won a Phi Beta Kappa Prize for the best scholarly work by a faculty member at the University of Virginia for his book, The Anatomy of Communist Takeovers, which he edited. His other books include: Yugoslavia Between East and West, Lenin on Trade Unions and Revolution and Red Flag Over Afghanistan: The Soviet Invasion of Afghanistan and its Consequences. He was also editor of Soviet Foreign Relations and World Communism, A Selected, Annotated Bibliography of 7,000 Books in 30 Languages and Witnesses to the Origins of the Cold War.
In addition to his scholarly work, Hammond was an active participant in university and departmental activities. He served on a multitude of committees including: Scholarship, Athletics, Non-Western Studies, Undergraduates, Foreign Students, Fulbright Fellowships and Truman Scholarships. He served on the University President's Special Search Committees, was Secretary of the Academic Faculty for six years and was a member of all of the Department of History Committees at one time or another.
During the critical civil rights period in the 1950's and 1960's, Hammond was a force for helping smooth the process of racial integration. With Paul Gaston, he helped found the Martin Luther King Chapter of the Council on Human Relations to recruit black students and faculty and to eliminate discrimination. This effort was also carried over into the local community where Hammond served as president of the Charlottesville Chapter of the Council on Human Relations and as a member of the Executive Committee of the local branch of the NAACP, promoting social justice in local schools, parks and other facilities.
On February 11, 1993, after having suffered a stroke, Hammond died in Charlottesville Virginia. He was survived by his widow Nancy, his son, Thomas Kent,and his stepchildren, Andrea Fritch Parle and Vernon Craig Fritch.
Scope and Content
The papers of Thomas Taylor Hammond, a distinguished professor of history (professor emeritus) from the University of Virginia, and a specialist in Russian and Slavic studies, contain ca. 4,000 items, (30 Hollinger boxes, 1 cubic box and 155 linear feet). The collection spans the time that he taught at the University, 1949-1992.
The papers are organized into eight series: Series I contains publications written by Hammond. Series II has background source materials (articles, lecture notes, scholarly papers and news clippings) used for teaching. Series III has course handouts and packets of reading material for students. There are also two course packets belonging to Professor Sablinsky's courses Hieu 244: Russia From Peter the Great to 1917 in the fall of 1986 and 1987. Series IV includes copies of exams that Hammond wrote for his courses. Series V includes scholarly papers written by others. Series VI contains student papers which are restricted. Series VII includes handouts and brochures that he gave to students to teach them how to research, apply for grants and become published. Series VIII deals with the correspondence of Professor Hammond.
Included in Series I, publications by Hammond, are eighteen articles that he wrote for many scholarly and international journals such as the Political Science Quarterly, Survey, Orbis, Foreign Affairs and the Journal of International Affairs. Also included are two articles in the National Geographic: "First Hand Look at the Soviet Union" (September 1959) and "An American in Moscow" (March 1966). There is also an article in the University of Virginia Alumni News, "The Outster of Khrushchev and Its Consequences" (May-June 1965). There are also many papers by Hammond dating from 1949 to 1984.
In series II there are articles and publications that Hammond collected for his teaching. Topics include every aspect of Russian life from culture (music, theatre and ballet), family values, economics and alcoholism to more political aspects such as, Russia's relationships with the rest of the world; political leaders; political change and influence; Bolsheviks; revolution; black market; espionage; cold war; the Cuban missile crisis and many more subjects. Some scholarly papers are included with the articles if the topics covered in the paper are closely related.
Alongside the folders of articles in Hammond's source material are folders of lecture notes on subjects that he taught. His notes show that he reviewed his lectures and tried to improve his teaching by studying what worked well in the classroom and how a topic could be shortened, lengthened or omitted to help students better understand the concepts that he taught.
In series III there are hand-outs and course packets (reading material) for the following courses (Box 22 and 23): Hieu 189; Hieu 244 #1; Hieu 244 #2; Hieu 383/583 (#1); Hieu 383/583 (#2); Hieu 384/584; Hieu 583; Hist 384/584 (#1); Hist 384/584 (#2) Hist 487/488; Hist 384/584/586; Hist 488; Hist 488K; and Hist 488R.
There are also lecture notes from Hammond's First Year Seminar: The Russian Revolution and miscellaneous articles. Also included in this series are outline notes from Professor Woodford "Woody" McClellan.
Series IV consists of master copies of exam questions that Hammond wrote for many of his courses. He has added notes on many of the exam copies indicating if the test was too hard or how he might change it in the future.
Series V of the collection includes professional papers that were written by scholars for various conferences. The papers in Box 25 and 26 are organized by the name of the conferences. There are additional papers written by scholars where the name of the conference is unknown. These are organized by the title of the papers. (Box 27)
The Conferences include: Academic Committee on Soviet Jewry, Discussion at the Academy of Sciences, Air Force Intelligence Conference on Soviet Affairs, Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association, Dominant Powers and Subordinate States Conference, Hoover Conference: "Fifty Years of Communism", Institute for the Study of the USSR, Kennan Institute Conference Paper on "USSR and Marxist Revolutions", Nationalism and the Soviet Union Conference: Implications for the Future, Proceedings of the Low-Intensity Warfare Conference, Research Conference on Communist Revolutions, Seminar on "Soviet National Security Decision Making", Southern Conference on Slavic Studies (5th Annual, Soviet Policy in the Third World Conference, St. Antony's College-Oxford Conference, and the Subcomittee on the Far East and Pacific of the Committee on Foreign Affairs.
Series VI consists of student papers including one by Charles Evans, the donor for this collection. The papers are graded and have restricted access.
Series VII contains advice on teaching and research that Professor Hammond provided for students through hand-outs and brochures.
Series VIII contains some correspondence of Professor Hammond. There is miscellaneous correspondence such as a letter from Hammond to an unknown recipient about ordering a dissertation "The Rise and Fall of the Bela Kun Regime 1919" by Frank Eckelt as well as a reference to personal information about his wife and her family in Prague; a letter from Fred Pryor of Swartmore College about speaking at a conference; and an invitation to an undergraduate mixer. There is also correspondence between Hammond and his assistant Charles Evans and a letter of reference for Evans.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into eight series. Within each series the papers are organized alphabetically by topic and chronologically within each folder.
Contents List
- Series I Articles, papers, and preliminary drafts by Hammond
  - Afghanistan and the Persian Gulf, Survey, v.26 no. 2, Spring 1982 p.83-101 Spring 1982 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Atomic Diplomacy Revisited Winter 1976 (Box-folder 1:2)
    Orbis, v.XIX, Winter 1976, no. 4
  - Brief History of Yugoslavia n.d. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Mid-European Studies Center of the Free Europe Committee, Frederick A. Praeger, New York, p.2-41
  - The Closed Shop Issue in World War II February 1943 (Box-folder 1:4)
    The North Carolina Law Review, February 1943, v.21, no.2, p.127-211
  - The Communist Take Over of Outer Mongolia 1975 (Box-folder 1:5)
    The History of Communist Takeovers, offprint of The Anatomy of Communist Takeovers, 1975, Yale University
  - The Cool War March 1956 (Box-folder 1:6)
    The New Leader, March 5, 1956, p.15-18
  - The Djilas Affair and Jugoslav Communism 1955 January (Box-folder 1:7)
    Reprinted from Foreign Affairs
  - Two articles: "Firsthand Look at the Soviet Union" and "An American In Moscow Russia's Capital" Sept. 1959; March 1966 (Box-folder 1:8)
    The National Geographic Magazine, v.126, no.3, Sept. 1959; v.129, no.3 March 1966 p.297-351
  - "How the Communists Conquered a French Trade Union" 1963 (Box-folder 1:9)
    Essays in Russian and Soviet History, NY, Columbia University Press, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1955
  - "Jugoslav Elections: Democracy in Small Doses" March 1955 (Box-folder 1:10)
    Political Science Quarterly, v. LXX, March 1955, no.1, p.57-74
  - "Lenin Authoritarianism Before the Revolution" 1955 (Box-folder 1:11)
    Continuity and Change in Russian and Soviet Thought, Harvard University Press, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1955
  - "Lenin on Russian Trade Unions Under Capitalism 1894-1904" Decmeber 1949 (Box-folder 1:12)
    The American Slavic and East European Review, v.VIII, no.4, Dec. 1949, p.275-288
  - "Moscow and Communist Takeovers" January-February 1976 (Box-folder 1:13)
    Problems of Communism, January-February 1976, p.48-67
  - "Nationalism and National Minorities In Eastern Europe" 1966 (Box-folder 1:14)
    The Virginia Quarterly Review, v.34, no.2, Spring 1958, p.277-291
  - "The Origin of National Communism" Spring 1958 (Box-folder 2:1)
    The Virginia Quarterly Review, v.34, no.2 Spring 1958, p. 277-291
  - "The Outster of Khrushchev and Its Consequences" May-June 1965 (Box-folder 2:2)
    University of Virginia Alumni News, v. LIII, May-June 1965, p.8-10; 33-37
  - "Revision Reconsidered" 1974 March (Box-folder 2:3)
    Reprinted from the Slavic Review, American Quarterly of Soviet and East European Studies, v.33, no.1, March 1974
  - "Will the Soviets Pull Out of Afghanistan?" 1983 Autumn, Winter (Box-folder 2:4)
    Survey, v.27, Autumn, Winter 1983, p.232-246
  - Papers by Hammond 1974; n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
    Including Bibliography on the Beginnings of the Cold War, 1941-1946; Communist Party; Congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union; Detente and Soviet Support for Revolutions
  - Preliminary drafts of papers by Hammond n.d.; 1967 (Box-folder 2:6)
    "Did the United States Use Atomic Diplomacy in Eastern Europe?"; "Is Communism Beginning To Wither Away?"; "Nationalism and National Minorities in Eastern Europe"; "Soviet Attitudes Toward Communist Takeovers Today"; "Revisionist Historians and the Origins of the Cold War In Eastern Europe"
- Series II Articles, lecture notes, and papers
  - Afghanistan-Articles 1963-1987 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Agriculture-Articles and scholarly papers 1960-1969 (Box-folder 3:2)
    Scholarly papers include "Under Khrushchev: The Lean Years", Nancy Nimitz, March 1965; The Private Sector In Soviet Agriculture", John W. De Pauw, U.S. Bureau of Census
  - Agriculture- Articles 1970-1982 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Agriculture- Lecture notes 1955; 1982 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Albania- Articles 1961-1966 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Alcoholism- Lecture notes and a publication 1971 (Box-folder 3:6)
    Publication: Alcoholism in the USSR, David E. Powell, reprinted from Survey, no.1 (78), Winter 1971, Ilford House, London
  - Alexander II Reforms-Lecture notes [1980-1983] (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Allende In Retrospect-Article 1974 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Allied American Intervention-Articles 1964; 1976 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Allied American Intervention- Lecture notes [1971-1986] (Box-folder 3:10)
  - American Foreign Policy-Articles 1958 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - American Recognition of Russia- Articles 1955-1972 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - American Recognition of Russia-Lecture notes 1971-1986 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - American Soviet Relations1931-1946- Articles 1950-1978 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - American Soviet Relations 1931-1946-Lecture notes 1972 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Andropov-Articles 1982-1984 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Andropov-Lecture notes 1982-1983 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Appeals of Communism-Articles and scholarly paper 1948-1986 (Box-folder 4:7)
    Scholarly paper includes "The Peasant as a Communist Revolutionary in Asia", Donald S. Zagoria
  - Appeals of Communism-Articles and scholarly papers 1988 (Box-folder 4:8)
    Scholarly papers include "Political Culture and the Attraction of Marxism-Leninism, Howard J. Wiarda; "Ideology and Nationalism in Attracting Third World Leaders to Communism", W. Raymond Duncan
  - Appeals of Communism-Lecture notes 1955-1987 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - Arms Control-Articles 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Arms Talks-Articles 1988-1991 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Beria-Articles 1950 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Berlin-Articles and oversize folded map 1958-1973 (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Black Market-Articles n.d. (Box-folder 4:14)
  - Black Market-Lecture notes n.d. (Box-folder 4:15)
  - Brezhnev-Articles 1965-1982 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Brezhnev-Lecture notes 1968-1989 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Early Brezhnev-Articles and Lecture notes 1965-1972 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Brezhnev succession-Articles 1973-1984 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Brezhnev succession-Lecture notes 1976-1982 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - British Soviet Relations 1919-1932-Lecture notes 1963-1986 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Bulganin-Articles 1955 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Soviet Censors on the Defensive-Articles 1967 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Chernenko-Articles 1984 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Chernenko-Lecture notes 1982 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Chicherin-Articles 1953 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - Chinese Revolution of 1927-Lecture notes 1926; 1969; n.d. (Box-folder 5:12)
  - CIA-Articles 1971-1977 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - CIA-Lecture notes n.d. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Civil War-Articles 1960 (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Civil War-Lecture notes 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5:16)
  - Class Systems and Mobility-Articles 1956-1980 (Box-folder 5:17)
  - Class Systems and Mobility-Lecture notes 1975-1978 (Box-folder 5:18)
  - Cold War-Articles 1945-1980 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Cold War-Articles 1968-1974 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Cold War-Articles 1970-1979 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Cold War-Articles 1945-1969 (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Cold War Origins-Lecture notes 1968; 1974 (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Cominterm-Lecture notes n.d. [1973-1978] (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Communist Front Organizations-Lecture notes 1922; 1955-1968 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Comimunist Front Organizations n.d. (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Communist Party-Articles 1970-1984 (Folder 7:1)
  - Communist Party-Lecture notes n.d. (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Nineteenth Congress-Articles 1952 (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Twernty-First Congress-Articles 1958-1959 (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Twenty-Third Congress-Articles and a paper 1966-1973 (Box-folder 7:5)
    paper: The 23rd Soviet Party Congress April 29,1966 by the Department of State
  - Twenty-fourth Congress-Articles 1971 (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Eighty-fourth CongressArticles 1969-1976 (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Conquest of the Borderlands 1969-1976 (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Conquest of the Borderlands-Lecture notes 1969-1976 (Box-folder 7:9)
  - Constitutional Development in Russia-Articles n.d. (Box-folder 7:10)
  - Cuba Missile Crisis-Articles 1962;1982 (Folder 7:11)
  - Culture: Music, Ballet, Theatre-Articles 1958-1969 (Box-folder 7:12)
  - Culture: Music, Ballet, Theatre-Lecture notes '976 (Box-folder 7:13)
  - Dedijer-Articles 1955-1971 (Box-folder 8:1)
  - De-Stalinization-Articles 1953-1962 (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Dissent-Lecture notes 1970-1982 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Dissent-Articles 1961-1971 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Dissent-Articles 1972-1983 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Doctor's Plot-Articles 1953-1956 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Dominican Republic-Articles 1965-1967 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Economics-Articles and scholarly paper 1966-1989 (Box-folder 8:8)
    paper-The Domestic Economy, Gregory Grossman
  - Economics-Lecture notes [1955-1982] (Box-folder 8:9)
  - Economic Reforms-Articles 1960-1972 (Box-folder 8:10)
  - Economic Reforms-Lecture notes 1963-1976 (Box-folder 8:11)
  - Economic Warfare-Articles 1957-1965 (Box-folder 8:12)
  - Education-Articles 1954-1980 (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Education-Lecture notes 1959-1982 (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Elections-Articles 1954-1970 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Elections-Lecture notes [1961-1984] (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Electoral System Reform-Article 1990 (Box-folder 9:5)
  - Espionage-Articles 1950-1983 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Espionage-Lecture notes n.d. (Box-folder 9:7)
  - Ethiopa-paper: The Union of Soviet Socialist Republics and the Horn of Africa 1977-1978, Wei Shou-yao 1985 (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Failure of Communism-Articles 1953; 1967 (Box-folder 9:9)
  - Failure of Communism-Lecture notes 1953 (Box-folder 9:10)
  - Far East-Lecture notes 1969-1986 (Box-folder 9:11)
  - Forced Labor-Articles 1953 (Box-folder 9:12)
  - Forced Labor-Lecture notes n.d. (Box-folder 9:13)
  - Foreign Policy-Articles 1954-1955 (Box-folder 10:1)
  - Foreign Policy-Articles 1956-1966 (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Foreign Policy-Articles 1961; 1962-1964 (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Foreign Policy-Lecture notes 1953-1955 (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Foreign Trade-Articles 1960; 1988-1990 (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Germany in 1920's-Articles n.d.; 1958; 1972 (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Germany in 1920's-Lecture notes 1967; 1973 (Box-folder 10:7)
  - German Revolutions 1918-1919-Articles [1964]; n.d. (Box-folder 10:8)
  - German Revolutions 1918-1919-Lecture notes 1976 (Box-folder 10:9)
  - Germany-Russia (Brest-Litovsk)-Lecture notes 1978 (Box-folder 10:10)
  - Germany and USSR 1939-1941-Articles 1954-1972 (Box-folder 10:11)
  - Germany and USSR 1939-1941-Lecture notes 1978 (Box-folder 10:12)
  - Gorbachev-Articles 1985-1988 (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Gorbachev 1989-Articles 1987-1991 (Box-folder 11:2)
  - Gorbachev-foreign Policy USSR and U.S.A.- Articles 1989-1990 (Box-folder 11:3)
  - Gorbachev and the Law-Articles 1988-1990 (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Gorbachev and Literature-Articles 1987-1990 (Box-folder 11:5)
  - Gorbachev Regime (Gertrude Greenslade)-Lecture notes 1987 (Box-folder 11:6)
  - Gorbachev and Religion-Articles 1988-1989 (Box-folder 11:7)
  - Government of Soviet Union-Articles 1949; 1958; 1963 (Box-folder 11:8)
  - Government of Soviet Union-Articles 1967-1975 (Box-folder 11:9)
  - Government of Soviet Union-Lecture notes n.d. (Box-folder 11:10)
  - Government Soviet (Local)-Articles 1958-1976 (Box-folder 11:11)
  - Government soviet (Local)-Lecture notes n.d. (Box-folder 11:12)
  - Housing-Articles 1950-1963 (Box-folder 11:13)
  - Housing-Lecture notes n.d. (Box-folder 11:14)
  - Hungary-Articles 1957-1970 (Box-folder 11:15)
  - Hungarian Revolution-Articles 1925; 1934; 1951; 1968; 1986 (Box-folder 11:16)
  - Hungarian Revolution-Lecture notes 1973-1982 (Box-folder 11:17)
  - Hungarian Revolution-Articles 1956 (Box-folder 11:18)
  - Imperial Russia-Article n.d. (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Indochina-Articles 1950-1963 (Box-folder 12:2)
  - Indonesia-Articles 1958-1966 (Box-folder 12:3)
  - Iran-Lecture notes 1969-1971 (Box-folder 12:4)
  - Intervention-Articles 1964-1986 (Box-folder 12:5)
  - Intervention Against Communism-Articles 1970-1983 (Box-folder 12:6)
  - Intervention Against Communism-Lecture notes 1979-1980 (Box-folder 12:7)
  - Intervention Project-Articles 1983-1985 (Box-folder 12:8)
  - Jewish Emigration-Articles 1974-1975 (Box-folder 12:9)
  - Jews-Articles 1953-1969 (Box-folder 12:10)
  - Jews-Articles 1970-1983 (Box-folder 12:11)
  - Jews-Lecture notes n.d.; 1972 (Box-folder 12:12)
  - Khrushchev-Articles and a paper 1955-1961 (Box-folder 13:1)
    paper- An Overview of latinAmerican Disputes and Conflicts, and a Case Study of Grenada, Larman C. Wilson
  - Khrushchev-Lecture notes 1n.d. [1977] (Box-folder 13:2)